{
  "reference_number": "9310",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "New Zealand is a very small country and has a minuscule global effect on any worldwide carbon emissions. When the large polluters\n of the planet, i.e. USA & China are prepared to do something meaningful then we join in, until then we are wasting our time and\n money pursuing this."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "No target at all until (1) has been achieved"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "By not setting any."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Change the target to allow New Zealand to compete on a level playing field. I feel the Zero Carbon Bill is a total waste of our\n resources, time and money. There are far more pressing things to address in this country that will result in a better environment to\n\n live, i.e youth crime, drug usage, educational standards, health, the list is long, but we make it hard when we go off on flights of\n fantasy, such as pursuing this bill."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Scrap the bill and its targets."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "see (5)"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "See (5)"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Do not set targets or budgets."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This sounds as if we are attempting to change the laws of physics. If there is a marked reduction in CO2 as a result of any efforts\n\nmade, vegetation will suffer, which in turn will cause any oxygen consuming life to suffer. Remove CO2 from the atmosphere and we\nall die. 3rd form biology teaches this."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The Govt. needs to find a way to work with volcanoes!! these spew more carbon into the atmosphere than ever we can hope to\n\nremove. The amount of carbon in the world is a constant, we can neither create nor destroy it. Encapsulating it in vegetation is the\nbest thing the world can do."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This whole Commission 'industry' is a huge waste of time and money, and as a taxpayer, it is my money and I object to it being wasted\non such things."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "See (11,) get rid of the Commission."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The expertise needed is Divine and therefore not available. Dismantle the CCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The Bill should be scrapped. Concentrate our resources on issues that will benefit our population and not try to hoodwink them into\na wild goose chase."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The only constant in the world is change. (Some clever person coined this phrase, but it is very true). For thousands, nay, millions of\nyears the climate on this planet has changed, Ice ages come and go. Warm periods come and go. The oil deposits in the Middle East\n\nare a result of decaying vegetation that grew there millions of years ago, the place is a desert now, why? it is due to naturally\noccurring changes our solar system produces, it is due to the laws of physics and we cannot change these, we can adapt tho'."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This is another Job creation scheme! it will produce meaningless data and not alter anything except drain the small resources of the\n\nGovts coffers."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "If one swings a bucket of water around in a circle the arc it describes is constant, due to the fact we have friction between our feet\n\nand the ground, if this attempted whilst standing in a small boat the result is very different, as we are now subject to the centrifugal\nforce of the bucket of water, but with no constant axis. This is in effect what the Sun is doing, except it has 9 planets spinning around\n\nand many are huge compared to the Earth. The sun therefore, having no means of axis fixation, will move in its own orbit. This will vary\naccording to the alignment of the planets. The Sun will move in relation to the Earth, therefore producing warm periods and cool\nperiods. This occurs over many thousands of years, history tells us of ice ages. Sir Issac Newton figured this out with his 3rd Law of\n\nMotion. This whole Zero Carbon Emission thing is whistling into the wind. The Govt should direct its energies and finances into things\nit can change and benefit the population of New Zealand and not buy into the hysteria of the moment."
    }
  ]
}
